The Life of Muhammadﷺ, The Madinan Period, Volume 1
By Imam Anwar Al_Awlaki,
اَعُوْذُ بِاللهِ مِنَّ الشِّيْطَانِ الرَّجِيْمِ ۝
بِسْمِ اللهِ الرَّحْمَانِ الرَّحِيْمَ۝
اَلْحَمْدُ لله ، وَالصَّلَاةُ وَالسَّلَامُ عَلى سَيِّدِنَا محمد وَعَلَى اَلِهِ وَصَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ تَسْلِيْمًا كَثِيْراَ
اَمَّا بَعد  ،
السلام علیكم ورحمة الله وبركاته
We talked about, consequences of the Battle of Badr(بدر)
and we said that now we have a serious problem of hypocrisy.
There was also another group in Madina
which posed threat to the newly formed Islamic State and the new Muslim community,
which is headed by the Messenger of Allah, Muhammadﷺ,
and that group is the Jewish tribes, the Jews.
Now we'll be talking about them in this session, probably for the entire session.
So, I want to state in the out start that when we are talking about, the history of the Muslim and Jewish relations,
when we talk about the Ayaat(آيات) of Qur'an and Ahadith(أحاديث) of Rasool Allah ﷺ that talk about the Jews,
we are not being anti Semitic.
In fact, a good portion of the Muslim Ummah(امة) are Semitic people to start with, the Arabs.
And we are not racists
and we do not claim the ethnic superiority of any particular ethnic group.
These are things that Muslims don't do or shouldn't do.
However, we speak about historical truths
and if these historical truths do not abide by the modern rules of political correctness,
that's not an issue with us as muslims.
We Muslims are not going to subject Qur'an and Sunnah(سنة) to rules of political correctness,
but we will subject political correctness to the rules of Qur'an and Sunnah(سنة).
So, what we are stating here are actual events that happened
and the consequences of these events
and these events occurred after Rasool Allah ﷺ has made an agreement
and we talked about that agreement, Al-Waseeqa(ألوثيقه), the covenant,
which was to govern the relationship of the Muslims and the Jews and the non Muslim Arabs, who were in Madina.
So in the beginning, Rasool Allah ﷺ was dealing with the Yahood(يهود), as citizens of Madina, citizens of the Islamic State.
This is how he approached them,
he didn't approach them with any hidden agenda,
he didn't approach the relationship with them with prejudgment and hatred.
Rasool Allah ﷺ started his relationship with them as people of the book,
who are supposed to be closer to the Muslims than the polytheists.
However, it was the Jews who started plotting against the Islamic State,
it was them, who were breaking their agreement with Rasool Allah ﷺ,
and it was them, who stood against Rasool Allah ﷺ by word and deed.
So, what was their response to Rasool Allah ﷺ and the Muslims.?
There are Ayaat(آيات) in Qur'an that were revealed talking specifically about the Yahood(يهود).
They were upset, from the outstart of the arrival of Rasool Allah ﷺ to Madina.
And we can sense that from the conversation that occurred with two of the leaders of Al-Yahood(اليهود) in Madina
Huyaye Ibn Akhtab(حيئي إبن أخطب) and his brother Abu Yasir(أبوياسر).
Safiyyah رضي الله عنها , the wife of Rasool Allah ﷺ, she says;
None of the children of my father or my uncle were more popular with them, both than I was.
She's referring to her popularity with her father and her uncle, Abu Yasir(أبوياسر).
She said: None of the children of my father or my uncle were more popular with them, both than I was.
Whatever child of theirs wanted their attention, it was always me they put first.
When the Messenger of Allah came to Quba'a(قباء)
the village of Bannu Amr Bin Auf(بنو عمرو بن عوف),
my father and my uncle Abu Yasir(ابوياسر) went to him early in the morning
and only returned at sunset.
So tired out, they could scarcely walk staggering from exhaustion.
So, here we're dealing with an event that occurred on the first day of the arrival of Rasool Allah ﷺ to Madina.
he is still in the outskirts of Madina, he's in Quba'a(قباء).
Safiyyah(صفيه) says, they came back that day, tired and worn out.
She said, I raised over to greet them, as was my custom,
but I swear neither so much as looked at me
I heard my uncle Abu Yasir(ابو ياسر) asked my father is that, he then?
So she, First of all, she's saying that they neglected me.
Obviously they were preoccupied with something else,
none of them picked her up,
and then she started hearing their conversation.
Abu Yasir(ابوياسر) is asking, Huyaye(حيئي) and said: Is that, he then?
He is talking about Muhammadﷺ, he's asking, is he the Prophet?
Is he the one mentioned in our books?
Is he the one prophesized by our Rabbis?
So, is that he then.?
Huyaye(حيئي) said; Yes, I swear by Allah.
Abu Yasir(ابو ياسر) said: You recognize him from his character and description then?
Huyaye(حيئي) said: I certainly do, in the name of Allah.
Abu Yasir(ابوياسر) goes, so how will you relate to him?
If he's a prophet? What does that mean, how will you respond to him?
Look at what Huyaye Ibn Akhtab(حيئي إبن أخطب) said, he said;
By Allah, I will be his enemy for as long as I live.
Subhaan Allah-Hil-Azeem(سُبْحَان الله العظيم),
so first, you recognize that he is the Prophet of Allah
and you know for sure that he's a prophet of Allah.
Rather than saying that I'm going to follow him,
you say, you will be his enemy for the rest of your life.
Why?
Well, the reason is clear.
It is because of envy,
and Huyaye(حيئي) is jealous that
the Prophet ended up being an Arab rather than a Jew.
And this envy caused him to disbelief Rasool Allah ﷺ.
And here we'll dealing with the worst type of kuffr(كفر)
and that is disbelieving in the truth when you know that it's the truth.
See, some people, they disbelieve, because they don't think that this is the truth.
They think that the Prophet is a liar,
they think that this is a fake religion,
they think that this was made up.
But then you have some people, who certainly know, that it is the truth.
Nevertheless, they still reject it
and this was the case, Huyaye Ibn Akhtab(حيئي إبن أخطب).
They would attempt to disunite the Muslims.
Ibn Is'haqq(اِبْنِ اِسْحَاقْ) said;
مَرَّ شَأْسُ بْنُ قَيْسٍ - وكانَ شَيْخًا قَدْ عَسا في الجاهِلِيَّةِ، عَظِيمَ الكُفْرِ، شَدِيدَ الضَّغَنِ عَلى المُسْلِمِينَ، شَدِيدَ الحَسَدِ لَهم
An old Jewish man, his name is Shaas Bin Qais(شاس بن قيس)
and this man was as Ibn Is'haqq(اِبْنِ اِسْحَاقْ) says;
Azeem-Ul-Kuffr(عظيم الكفر), Deep in Kuffr(كفر),
شَدِيْدُ طَّغْنِيْ عَلَى الْمُسْلِمِيْنْ،
And he has so much hatred of the Muslims.
He saw that Al-Aos and Al-Khazraj(ألاوس والخزرج) are united.
He saw that they're now sitting together in the same gathering
and these were people who were at each other's throats, before Islam.
These were people, who were enemies of each other.
Now, because of Islam, they were united, they were one.
So, this Jewish man wasn't very happy.
And he said;
قَدِجْتَمَعَ مَلَاءُ بَنِيْ قَيْلَهْ بِهَذِهِ الْبِلَادْ لَا وَللَّهِ مَا لَنَا مَعَ هُمْ اِذَجْتَمَعَ مَلَاءَهُمْ بِهَا مِنْ قَرَارْ
He said, the Al-Aos and Al-Khazraj(ألاوس والخزرج) are united in this land.
And In the name of Allah, we have no place here, as long as they are united.
Our survival as Jews in Madina is based on the disunity of the Arabs.
And as long as they are united, we are at risk.
So, he tells a young Jewish man,
who was sitting with Al-Aos and Al-Khazraj(ألاوس والخزرج) in the same gathering
to start reminding them about their days of war,
bring up the day of Buath(بعاث), bring up the Battle of so and so,
bring up the Battle of so and so, narrate some of that poetry
and instigate, a fight among them.
So, this young man sits between them,
and he starts bringing up some lines of poetry that talks about the heroic acts of one tribe against the other.
And slowly he was able to cause a shouting match between the two parties.
And after that they stood up and challenged each other to combat,
and they agreed that we will meet in Al-Harrah Fidh Zahira(ألهرة في الظاهره),
we will meet in such and such place
let's go and arm ourselves.
So, war was about to start all over again.
See how words can cause so much evil.
A war could start because of one word.
That's why Allahعَزّوجَلّ says;
وَقُلْ لِعِبَادِي يَقُولُوا الَّتِي هِيَ أَحْسَنُ ۚ إِنَّ الشَّيْطَانَ يَنْزَغُ بَيْنَهُمْ ۚ إِنَّ الشَّيْطَانَ كَانَ لِلْإِنْسَانِ عَدُوًّا مُبِينًا۝
"Tell my servants to say good words, because Shaytan(شيطان) is there to disunite them."
So, a Muslims should be very careful about what they say.
The news was delivered to Rasool Allah ﷺ and Rasool Allah ﷺ rushed forward.
While they were making an appointment on where to meet,
to start the war all over again.
And Rasool Allah ﷺ said;
O Muslims fear Allah.
Are you to resume the enmity of ignorance?
When I am still among you?
Are you going to bring back Jahilliyah(جاهليه), while I'm still alive and living among you?
After Allah has guided you to believe in Islam and submit to Him?
Do you forget Allah's blessing as He has saved you from ignorance and disbelief
and planted love and friendliness in your hearts, instead of hostility?
Rasool Allah ﷺ is reminding them that this unity was a favor from Allah.
Don't throw it behind your backs.
Allah has brought you together,
Allah has sent you, His Messenger,
Allah has made you love each other.
The love that now exists among the Sahabah(صحابه) is unsurpassed.
How can you throw that behind your back and go back to the time of Jahilliyyah(جاهليه),
you know how bad Jahilliyyah(جاهليه) was?
Now since you have tasted Eeman(ايمان), you will know how evil and bad Kuffr(كفر) was.
You know, Rasool Allah ﷺ says that you will only taste the sweetness of faith, if three things happen.
One of them Rasool Allah ﷺ said
that you would hate to go back to Kuffr(كفر) like you would hate to be thrown in the fire.
So, a person who taste Eeman(إيمان) and knows how beautiful Eeman(إيمان) is,
knows how bad and depressing Kuffr(كفر) is.
And Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله) these words of Rasool Allah ﷺ had so much effect on them,
they started hugging each other.
These men who were just thinking about going to war, are now hugging each other,
and asking each other for forgiveness.
Allahعَزّوجَلّ says;
قُلْ يَا أَهْلَ الْكِتَابِ لِمَ تَكْفُرُونَ بِآيَاتِ اللَّهِ وَاللَّهُ شَهِيدٌ عَلَىٰ مَا تَعْمَلُونَ۝
قُلْ يَا أَهْلَ الْكِتَابِ لِمَ تَصُدُّونَ عَنْ سَبِيلِ اللَّهِ مَنْ آمَنَ
لِمَ تَصُدُّونَ عَنْ سَبِيلِ اللَّهِ مَنْ آمَنَ تَبْغُونَهَا عِوَجًا وَأَنْتُمْ شُهَدَاءُ ۗ
وَمَا اللَّهُ بِغَافِلٍ عَمَّا تَعْمَلُونَ۝
Say, O People of the Scripture.
Why do you disbelieve in the verses of Allah?
While Allah is witness over, what you do.
Say, O People of the Scripture,
Why do you avert from the way of Allah those who believe,
seeking to make it seem deviant
while you are witnesses to the truth.
And Allah is not unaware of what you do.
And Allahعَزّوجَلّ says;
يَا أَيُّهَا الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا إِنْ تُطِيعُوا فَرِيقًا مِنَ الَّذِينَ أُوتُوا الْكِتَابَ
إِنْ تُطِيعُوا فَرِيقًا مِنَ الَّذِينَ أُوتُوا الْكِتَابَ يَرُدُّوكُمْ بَعْدَ إِيمَانِكُمْ كَافِرِينَ۝
O, you, who have believed, if you obey a party of those, who are given the Scripture,
they would turn you back after your belief to being unbelievers.
So, Allahعَزّوجَلّ says there's only one result of following the People of the Book
and that is, it will make you revert back to disbelief.
So, this is a warning to the Muslims from following Ahl-lil-Kitaab(اَهْل الْكِتَاب), the People of the Book,
and then Allah says,
وَكَيْفَ تَكْفُرُونَ وَأَنْتُمْ تُتْلَىٰ عَلَيْكُمْ آيَاتُ اللَّهِ وَفِيكُمْ رَسُولُهُ ۗ
وَمَنْ يَعْتَصِمْ بِاللَّهِ فَقَدْ هُدِيَ إِلَىٰ صِرَاطٍ مُسْتَقِيمٍ۝
So, following the book is a one way road that ends in disbelief.
And then Allah says;
وَكَيْفَ تَكْفُرُونَ وَأَنْتُمْ تُتْلَىٰ عَلَيْكُمْ آيَاتُ اللَّهِ وَفِيكُمْ رَسُولُهُ ۗ
وَمَنْ يَعْتَصِمْ بِاللَّهِ فَقَدْ هُدِيَ إِلَىٰ صِرَاطٍ مُسْتَقِيمٍ۝
O you, who have believed fear Allah,
as He should be feared, and do not die except as Muslims,
and hold firmly to the rope of Allah all together, and do not become divided.
See, because Shaas Bin Qais(شاس بن قيس) wanted to cause division among them,
Allahعَزّوجَلّ is warning them.
And remember the favor of Allah upon you,
when you were enemies, and he brought your hearts together and you became, by his favor, brothers.
And you were on the edge of a pot of the fire and he saved you, from it.
Thus does Allah make clear to you, His verses that you may be guided
and Let there be arising from you a nation inviting to all that is good,
enjoining what is right and forbidding what is wrong,
and these will be the successful.
And do not be like the ones, who became divided and deferred after the clear proofs had come to them
and those will have a great punishment.
These are some of the verses, revealed talking about Al-Yahood(يهود)
and Allahعَزّوجَلّ says,
in another Ayaah(آية) that is referring to another problem
that the Yahood(يهود) suffered from, another disease and that is blasphemy.
They would speak ill about Rasool Allah ﷺ,
they would speak ill about the Muslims,
they would speak ill about Islam,
they would speaking about Allahعَزّوجَلّ.
Allahعَزّوجَلّ says; And this Ayaah(آية) was revealed,
after a conversation happened between Abu Bakr(ابو بكر) and Fanhaas(فينحاس).
Fanhaas(فينحاس) was one of the Jewish rabbis in Madina
and Abu Bakr Siddique رضي الله عنه was giving him Da'wah(دعوة).
So, Fanhaas(فينحاس) responded by saying
your God is poor, and we are rich.
How can He ask you to give charity?
If your God is rich, He wouldn't be asking you to give Him money.
That proves that he's a need, and we are rich, and He needs us.
So, Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) was quite upset with those words,
you know, even though he's giving him Da'wah(دعوة) before,
but he started punching him in the face.
So, Fanhaas(فينحاس) rushes back to Rasool Allah ﷺ, complaining.
He said: This is what Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) did to me.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ told Abu Bakr(ابوبكر), why did you hit him?
Abu Bakr(ابو بكر) said: because he said this and that.
Fanhaas(فينحاس) denied that he said, those words.
So, Allahعَزّوجَلّ reveals the Ayaah(آية) saying;
لَقَدْ سَمِعَ اللَّهُ قَوْلَ الَّذِينَ قَالُوا إِنَّ اللَّهَ فَقِيرٌ وَنَحْنُ أَغْنِيَاءُ
سَنَكْتُبُ مَا قَالُوا وَقَتْلَهُمُ الْأَنْبِيَاءَ بِغَيْرِ حَقٍّ وَنَقُولُ ذُوقُوا عَذَابَ الْحَرِيقِ
ذَٰلِكَ بِمَا قَدَّمَتْ أَيْدِيكُمْ وَأَنَّ اللَّهَ لَيْسَ بِظَلَّامٍ لِلْعَبِيدِ۝
Allah has certainly heard the statement of those Jews, who said;
Indeed, Allah is poor, while we are rich,
We will record what they said and their killing of the prophets without right and We'll say,
taste the punishment of the burning fire.
That is for what your hands have put forth,
and Allah is not ever unjust to His servants.
And they would speak ill about the Muslim.
So Allahعَزّوجَلّ said;
لَتُبْلَوُنَّ فِي أَمْوَالِكُمْ وَأَنْفُسِكُمْ
وَلَتَسْمَعُنَّ مِنَ الَّذِينَ أُوتُوا الْكِتَابَ مِنْ قَبْلِكُمْ وَمِنَ الَّذِينَ أَشْرَكُوا أَذًى كَثِيرًا ۚ
وَإِنْ تَصْبِرُوا وَتَتَّقُوا فَإِنَّ ذَٰلِكَ مِنْ عَزْمِ الْأُمُورِ۝
You will surely be tested in your possessions and in yourselves.
And you will surely hear from those, who were given the Scripture before you,
and from those, who associate others with Allah much abuse.
Allahعَزّوجَلّ is telling the Muslims, This is expected.
They will make negative statements about you,
their newspapers will write blasphemous things about you,
their media will accuse you have things that are not true, this is only to be expected.
لَتَسْمَعُنَّ مِنَ الَّذِينَ أُوتُوا الْكِتَابَ مِنْ قَبْلِكُمْ وَمِنَ الَّذِينَ أَشْرَكُوا أَذًى كَثِيرًا ۚ
And then Allahعَزّوجَلّ says but if you are patient,
and fear Allah, indeed that is of the matters worthy of determination.
Their propaganda will not affect Islam or the Muslims,
as long as the Muslims are patient and have Taqwa(تقوى).
Because the truth remains and lies vanish.
And they were disrespectful of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
They came to him once and they were saying;
اَلسَّامُ عَلَيْكَ يَا رَسُوْلَ الله
Now this sounds very close to,
اَلسَّلَامُ عَلَيْكَ يَا رَسُوْلَ الله
So, they will take out the laam(ل) The L,
Instead of Salaam(سلام) they would say Sam(سام)
And اَسَّامُ عَلَيْكَ يَا رَسُوْلَ الله could mean may death befall you,
may death befall you.
So, Ayesha(عائشه) was very upset and she said;
اَسَّامُ عَلَيْكَمْ
You sons of monkeys and pigs and she was cursing them.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ said; Don't say that, O Ayesha(عائشه)
because Allahعَزّوجَلّ doesn't like foul language,
and then Allahعَزّوجَلّ reveal the Ayaah(آية).
أَلَمْ تَرَ إِلَى الَّذِينَ نُهُوا عَنِ النَّجْوَىٰ ثُمَّ يَعُودُونَ لِمَا نُهُوا عَنْهُ
وَيَتَنَاجَوْنَ بِالْإِثْمِ وَالْعُدْوَانِ وَمَعْصِيَتِ الرَّسُولِ
وَإِذَا جَاءُوكَ حَيَّوْكَ بِمَا لَمْ يُحَيِّكَ بِهِ اللَّهُ
وَيَقُولُونَ فِي أَنْفُسِهِمْ لَوْلَا يُعَذِّبُنَا اللَّهُ بِمَا نَقُولُ ۚ
حَسْبُهُمْ جَهَنَّمُ يَصْلَوْنَهَا ۖ فَبِئْسَ الْمَصِيرُ۝
Have you not considered those, who were forbidden from private conversation,
i.e. ridicule, and conspiracy.
Then they return to that which they were forbidden and converse,
among themselves about sin and aggression and disobedience to the messenger.
And when they come to you, they greet you with that word,
by which Allah does not greet you and say among themselves,
Why does Allah not punish us, for what we say?
So, they would say, we are speaking these ill words about Rasool Allah ﷺ, and nothing's happening to us.
So, this is evidence that he is not really the Messenger of Allah
Allahعَزّوجَلّ said, sufficient for them is hell,
which they will enter to burn and retched is the destination.
The Yahood(يهود) was also support the hypocrites
and they were the spiritual advisors to the hypocrites.
Allahعَزّوجَلّ says;
وَإِذَا لَقُوا الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا قَالُوا آمَنَّا
وَإِذَا خَلَوْا إِلَىٰ شَيَاطِينِهِمْ قَالُوا إِنَّا مَعَكُمْ إِنَّمَا نَحْنُ مُسْتَهْزِئُونَ۝
And when they meet those, who believe they say we believe
but when they are alone, with their evil ones,
they say, and the evil ones here is referring to Al-Yahood(اليهود).
They say; Indeed, we are with you, we were only mockers.
And Allahعَزّوجَلّ says about the Munafiqeen(منافقين) also;
إِنَّ الَّذِينَ ارْتَدُّوا عَلَىٰ أَدْبَارِهِمْ مِنْ بَعْدِ مَا تَبَيَّنَ لَهُمُ الْهُدَى ۙ الشَّيْطَانُ سَوَّلَ لَهُمْ وَأَمْلَىٰ لَهُمْ۝
ذَٰلِكَ بِأَنَّهُمْ قَالُوا لِلَّذِينَ كَرِهُوا مَا نَزَّلَ اللَّهُ سَنُطِيعُكُمْ فِي بَعْضِ الْأَمْرِ ۖ وَاللَّهُ يَعْلَمُ إِسْرَارَهُمْ۝
Indeed, those who reverted back to disbelief
After guidance had become clear to them.
Satan enticed them and prolonged hope for them.
That is because they say to those, who disliked, what Allah has sent down,
this is referring to Al-Yahood(اليهود).
That is because they said, to those who disliked what Allah sent down,
we will obey you in part of the matter,
and Allah knows what they conceal.
So, Allahعَزّوجَلّ is saying
that if you only obey them, in part of the matter, not all of it,
if you only obey them in a small thing,
that is sufficient to classify a person as somebody who has left the fold of Islam,
somebody who's a Munafiq(منافق).
So, as a Muslims, we need to be very careful about this issue,
and not to fall into the prey of being seduced by Al-Yahood(اليهود) and An-Nasarah(النصارى).
And Allahعَزّوجَلّ says;
أَلَمْ تَرَ إِلَى الَّذِينَ تَوَلَّوْا قَوْمًا غَضِبَ اللَّهُ عَلَيْهِمْ مَا هُمْ مِنْكُمْ وَلَا مِنْهُمْ
مَا هُمْ مِنْكُمْ وَلَا مِنْهُمْ وَيَحْلِفُونَ عَلَى الْكَذِبِ وَهُمْ يَعْلَمُونَ۝
أَعَدَّ اللَّهُ لَهُمْ عَذَابًا شَدِيدًا ۖ
إِنَّهُمْ سَاءَ مَا كَانُوا يَعْمَلُونَ۝
اِتَّخَذُوا أَيْمَانَهُمْ جُنَّةً فَصَدُّوا عَنْ سَبِيلِ اللَّهِ فَلَهُمْ عَذَابٌ مُهِينٌ۝
Have you not considered, those who make allies of a people with whom Allah has become angry.
And the people whom Allah has become angry as it is, in Surat-El-Fatiha(سورة الفاتحه), is Al-Yahood(اليهود),
they are neither of you nor of them, and they swear to untruth
while they know, they are lying.
Allah has, prepared for them a severe punishment.
Indeed, it was evil that they were doing.
They took their false oath as a cover,
so they averted people from the way of Allah and for them is a humiliating punishment.
And another thing that Al-Yahood(اليهود) were doing in Madina,
they were trying to block the path of people becoming Muslim.
So, for example, with Abdullah Bin Salaam(عبدالله بن سلام), immediately, as soon as he became Muslim,
they started accusing him of being a liar and accusing him of being unfaithful to his people
and to his religion and all that, we already talked about his story.
And they would not only do that with Abdullah Bin Salaam(عبدالله بن سلام),
they would even do it with the Arabs who become Muslim.
They'd tell them that your religion is better than their religion and all of that.
When it should be expected that Yahood(يهود) will consider the Muslims to be closer to them,
than the pagan worshippers, but that wasn't the case.
So, obviously, all of this would lead the Muslims and the Yahood(يهود) to confrontation.
You know, you can't have all of this happening
without Rasool Allah ﷺ responding to it.
So, they were on a collision course.
And after the Battle of Badr(بدر),
Rasool Allah ﷺ went to the Yahood(يهود) of Bannu Qainuqah(بنوقينقاع),
who were the closest to the Muslims, in terms of location, they were living in Madina itself,
unlike Bannu Quraidha(بنو قريظة) and Bannu An-Nadhir(بنو نضير),
who were living on the outskirts of Madina.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ goes to the Yahood(يهود) of Bannu Qainuqah(بنوقينقاع).
And he speaks to them, he said: O Jews, beware of Allah afflicting you, as He did Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ is telling them; Take heed at what happened.
You've seen how Allah humiliated Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) and how He has given His Prophet victory.
Do not let the same thing happened to you.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ here is delivering a warning to them
because of all of their plotting and planning against him
and all of the Fitna(فتنه) that they were causing among the Muslims, Rasool Allah ﷺ went to warn them.
He's giving them Naseeha(نصيحه), O, Jews, Beware of Allah afflicting you, as He did Quraish(قُرَيْشْ),
and so accept Islam,
you well know that I am a Prophet sent with a mission,
you find that to be so in your book, and in Allah's pact with you.
What was their response?
They said; Muhammad(محمد), do you think, we are your people?
Don't delude yourself,
just because you did battle with those who lack knowledge of warfare.
And so you could take advantage of them.
If you fight against us, you'll find us to be the real men.
So, the Yahood(يهود) are saying that you are fought against people who have no experience with war.
People who don't know the tactics of war, they don't have the experience.
But if you fight against us you'll know that we are real men.
Allahعَزّوجَلّ said;
قُلْ لِلَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا سَتُغْلَبُونَ وَتُحْشَرُونَ إِلَىٰ جَهَنَّمَ ۚ
وَبِئْسَ الْمِهَادُ ۝
قَدْ كَانَ لَكُمْ آيَةٌ فِي فِئَتَيْنِ الْتَقَتَا ۖ
فِئَةٌ تُقَاتِلُ فِي سَبِيلِ اللَّهِ وَأُخْرَىٰ كَافِرَةٌ يَرَوْنَهُمْ مِثْلَيْهِمْ رَأْيَ الْعَيْنِ ۚ
وَاللَّهُ يُؤَيِّدُ بِنَصْرِهِ مَنْ يَشَاءُ ۗ
إِنَّ فِي ذَٰلِكَ لَعِبْرَةً لِأُولِي الْأَبْصَارِ۝
You have vision, you learn a lesson from that.
But the Yahood(يهود) were so stubborn, they refused to accept the advice of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
So, one day, and we're talking about right after the Battle of Badr(بدر),
a Muslim woman goes to the marketplace,
which as we said the jewelry market was controlled by the Jews.
So this Muslim woman went to sell or trade, some jewelry that she had.
So, she sits next to this store.
She's sitting on the floor.
And she gives her jewelry to the Jewish owner at this shop.
So, some Jews were gathering and they asked her to uncover her face.
She refused.
So, the owner of the store, he goes behind her without her knowing.
And he pins, the bottom of her dress to her back.
Now when she was sitting on the floor obviously her dress would be dragging on the floor.
So, when he pinned it to her back, she didn't feel that,
she was unaware of what he was doing.
But when she stood up, what happened is that, she was exposed
because of the dress being pinned to her back when she stood up,
her legs or part of her Auwra(عورة) was exposed.
So, she screamed, a Muslim, who was there and saw what happened,
attacked the Yahoodi(يهودي) and killed him.
And then the Jews ganged up against the Muslim and killed him.
The news was delivered to Rasool Allah ﷺ immediately.
He called the army and went to Bannu Qainuqah(بنوقينقاع) and laid siege to their forts.
Immediately, No questions asked.
The Muslim woman she was violated, this is an invitation to war.
Rasool Allah ﷺ laid siege to their forts for 15 days.
And these Yahood(يهود), who were bragging about their skills as fighters,
and their training, and the weakness of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
Were now shaking in their forts.
And they were willing to surrender.
So, Abdullah Bin Ubaye(عبدالله بن ابيئ), who was their ally in Jahiliyyag(جاهليه),
goes to Rasool Allah ﷺ and tries to appeal for his allies.
Ubadah Bin Samit(عبادة بن صامت), who was also their ally.
Both Abdullah Bin Ubaye(عبدالله بن ابيئ) and Ubadah Bin Samit(عبادة بن صامت), were equally the allies of Bannu Qainuqah(بنوقينقاع).
They both went to Rasool Allah ﷺ but look at the difference in the position of these two men,
Ubadah Bin Samit(عبادة بن صامت) was now a good Muslim.
So, he goes to Rasool Allah ﷺ and says;
Messenger, of Allah, My only loyalty is to Allah
He, His Messenger and the believers,
I renounced the alliance with those unbelievers and I will give them no support whatsoever.
So, he does this at his own initiative.
It's not Rasool Allah ﷺ, who invited him,
He goes to Rasool Allah and makes it known, that O Rasool Ullah,
Yes, I was their ally in the time of Jahilliyyah(جاهليه), and this alliances is old.
And we are fought together in many occasions.
But right now, I'm announcing that my loyalty goes to Allah, Rasool Ullah and the believers
and I renounced my ties with the people of Bannu Qainuqah(بنوقينقاع).
While Abdullah Bin Ubaye(عبدالله بن ابيئ) goes to Rasool Allah ﷺ and says; Be good to my allies,
Be good to my allies. Rasool Allah ﷺ does not answer back.
So, then Abdullah Bin Ubaye(عبدالله بن ابيئ) goes to Rasool Allah ﷺ another time, and said: Be good to my allies.
Rasool Allah ﷺ does not respond back.
So, Abdullah Bin Ubaye(عبدالله بن ابي) puts his hand, in the pocket of Rasool Allah ﷺ and pulls him
and refuses to let him go, and then said, Be good to my allies.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ, told him; Let me go.
And the narrator of this Hadith(حديث) said, The face of Rasool Allah ﷺ became angry,
you can see anger in the face of Rasool Allah ﷺ, he is telling Abdullah Bin Ubaye(عبدالله بن ابي),
وَيْحَكَ اَرْسِلْنِيْ
Woe to you, let me go.
And Abdullah Bin Ubaye(عبدالله بن ابي) is holding tight to Rasool Allah ﷺ and said;
I will not let you go, until you are good to my allies.
They are 700 fighters,
who protected me against all my enemies.
And now you want to mow them down in one morning.
I am a man, who fears the terms of fortune.
I'm not gonna let you go, until you let them free.
They have helped me in numerous occasions
and now you just want to execute all of these men in one day.
Rasool Allah ﷺ told him, They are yours. They are yours.
Rasool Allah ﷺ, let them free.
So, the people of Bannu Qainuqah(بنوقينقاع) were set free, they were allowed to leave.
And the one, who would administer their traveling was Ubadah Bin Samit(عبادة بن صامت),
and they traveled to Ash-sham(الشام), Syria.
Their money was taken as Ghaneemah(غنيمه), as booty of war and was distributed among the Muslims.
Some Ayaat(آيات) were revealed regarding Abdullah Bin Ubaye(عبدالله بن ابي) and Ubadah Bin Samit(عبادة بن صامت)
because this showed the position of both men regarding their loyalty and their alliance to Al-Yahood(اليهود).
Allahعَزّوجَلّ says;
يَا أَيُّهَا الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا لَا تَتَّخِذُوا الْيَهُودَ وَالنَّصَارَىٰ أَوْلِيَاءَ ۘ
بَعْضُهُمْ أَوْلِيَاءُ بَعْضٍ ۚ
وَمَنْ يَتَوَلَّهُمْ مِنْكُمْ فَإِنَّهُ مِنْهُمْ ۗ
إِنَّ اللَّهَ لَا يَهْدِي الْقَوْمَ الظَّالِمِينَ۝
O you, who has believed!
Do not take the Jews and the Christians as allies,
they are in fact, allies of one another.
And whoever is an ally to them among you, then indeed he is one of them.
Indeed, Allah guides, not the wrong doing people.
So, you see those in whose hearts is disease, i.e. hypocrisy
hastening into associating with them,
saying; We are afraid the misfortune may strike us.
You see, this talking about Abdullah Bin Ubaye(عبدالله بن ابي).
So, he's worried that disaster might befall him, if his alliance with Yahood(يهود) is revoked
somehow, he thinks that his protection lies with them.
If I don't keep this alliance, evil will befall me,
something will happen,
so he doesn't have Tawakkul(توكل) in Allahعَزّوجَلّ, he's afraid.
فَتَرَى الَّذِينَ فِي قُلُوبِهِمْ مَرَضٌ يُسَارِعُونَ فِيهِمْ
يَقُولُونَ نَخْشَىٰ أَنْ تُصِيبَنَا دَائِرَةٌ ۚ
فَعَسَى اللَّهُ أَنْ يَأْتِيَ بِالْفَتْحِ أَوْ أَمْرٍ مِنْ عِنْدِهِ فَيُصْبِحُوا
فَيُصْبِحُوا عَلَىٰ مَا أَسَرُّوا فِي أَنْفُسِهِمْ نَادِمِينَ۝
We are afraid a misfortune may strike us
but perhaps Allah will bring conquest or decision from Him
and they will become over what they have been concealing within themselves regretful.
Meaning Allah will give the believers victory
and they will win against these people, whom you consider allies and think that they're the ones who will protect you.
And then Allah says;
وَيَقُولُ الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا أَهَٰؤُلَاءِ الَّذِينَ أَقْسَمُوا بِاللَّهِ جَهْدَ أَيْمَانِهِمْ ۙ إِنَّهُمْ لَمَعَكُمْ ۚ
حَبِطَتْ أَعْمَالُهُمْ فَأَصْبَحُوا خَاسِرِينَ۝
يَا أَيُّهَا الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا مَنْ يَرْتَدَّ مِنْكُمْ عَنْ دِينِهِ فَسَوْفَ يَأْتِي اللَّهُ بِقَوْمٍ
فَسَوْفَ يَأْتِي اللَّهُ بِقَوْمٍ يُحِبُّهُمْ وَيُحِبُّونَهُ
أَذِلَّةٍ عَلَى الْمُؤْمِنِينَ أَعِزَّةٍ عَلَى الْكَافِرِينَ۝
يُجَاهِدُونَ فِي سَبِيلِ اللَّهِ وَلَا يَخَافُونَ لَوْمَةَ لَائِمٍ ۚ
ذَٰلِكَ فَضْلُ اللَّهِ يُؤْتِيهِ مَنْ يَشَاءُ ۚ وَاللَّهُ وَاسِعٌ عَلِيمٌ۝
And those who believe will say;
Are these the ones who swore by Allah, their strongest oath that indeed they will be with you.
Their deeds have become worthless and they have become losers.
O, you, who have believed whoever of you, should revert from His religion.
Allah will bring forth in place of them a people, He will love and who will love Him,
who are humble toward the believers,
powerful against the disbelievers,
they strike in the cause of Allah.
They strive meaning fight Jihad(جهاد) in the cause of Allah and do not fear the blame of a critic.
So, this Ayaah(آية) has the attributes of At-Taefah Al-Mansoura(ألطائفة منصورة), the victorious party.
Again, Allah will bring forth, a people He will love and who will love Him.
So, number one, Allah loves them.
Number two, they love Allah.
Who are humble towards the believers, that's number three,
powerful against the disbelievers, number four.
They strive, they fight Jihad(جهاد) in the cause of Allah, number five,
and do not fear the blame of a critic, that's number six.
They don't care about what the media will say about them.
They don't care about what so, and so will say about them.
They don't care what the disbelievers say about them,
as long as it pleases Allahعَزّوجَلّ. That's enough.
That is the favor of Allah, He bestows it upon whom He wills,
and Allah is all encompassing and knowing.
وَمَنْ يَتَوَلَّ اللَّهَ وَرَسُولَهُ وَالَّذِينَ آمَنُوا
فَإِنَّ حِزْبَ اللَّهِ هُمُ الْغَالِبُونَ۝
Your ally is none but Allah, and therefore His Messenger and those who have believed
indeed the party of Allah, they will be the predominant.
See, Ubadah Bin Samit(عبادة بن صامت)  was approached by Abdullah Bin Ubaye(عبدالله بن ابيئ),
and Abdullah Bin Ubaye(عبدالله بن ابيئ) told him,
how are you going to revoke your alliance with these people,
who have helped you on such and such day and so and so, and he would go on.
Ubadah(عبادة) said;
تَغَيَّرَتِ الْقُلُوْبْ وَ مَحَى الاِسْلَامُ و العهُوْدْ اَمَا ولله اِنَّكَ لَمعصمٌ بِاَمْرٍ سَتَرَا غَيَّه’ غَدًا
He said; Now hearts are different.
And Islam has erased all of the former alliances,
and you are holding on to something, you will see that it is wrong, tomorrow,
you will realize that it's wrong tomorrow.
So Ubadah(عبادة) is saying;
Give up these thoughts that we have
because you will realize that you have taken the wrong coarse of action.
So Allahعَزّوجَلّ, here is confirming with Ubadah(عبادة) said
that if your loyalty goes to Allah, His messenger and the believers,
They are the ones who will be victorious in the end.
So, In other words, Abdullah Bin Ubaye(عبدالله بن ابي) was betting on the losing horse.
There was a woman called Asmaa Bint Marwan(أسماء بنت مروان).
This woman was gathering people to fight against the Muslims.
And she would spread lies about the Muslims.
So, a man called Umair Al-Khatmi(عمير ألختمي), killed her.
So, he goes to Rasool Allah ﷺ and said; Is that what I did wrong?
Rasool Allah ﷺ told him.
نَصَرْتَ للهَ وَ رَسُوْلَه’ يَا عُمَيْرْ
You have assisted Allah and His messenger, O Umair(عمير).
And then Rasool Allah ﷺ said;
لا ينتطح فيها عنزان
This thing that you did, No two Rams will butt heads over,
meaning that this is an issue that there should be no dispute about, what you did was right.
Abu Afq Al-Yahoodi(ابوعفك أليهودي), this was a Jewish man
and he was also inspiring others to fight against the Muslims.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ said; Who will rid us of Abu Afq (ابو عفك),
and he was also assassinated by the Muslims because of his evil,
but the most famous assassination of all, was that of Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف).
And his story is famous, it's in Al-Bukhari(البخاريْ), it's also narrated by Ibn Is'haaq(إبن اسحاق) and other scholars.
Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف), his father was an Arab, from the tribe of Tae(طئي).
He got married to a Jewish woman from Bannu Nadhir(بنو نضير).
So Ka'ab(كعب), became a Jew.
So, Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف), even though his father was Arab, but he was a Jew.
He followed the religion of his mother.
And he was a wealthy man, he was very eloquent, he was good poet
and he was respected, among the Arabs, he had a good position,
wealthy, well connected, famous.
Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف) was leading a media campaign, against the Muslims.
He was very active in his animosity towards Islam.
After the Battle of Badr(بدر), he lamented the battle in some words of poetry,
in which he shows that he expresses, his sorrow at what happened to the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ)
and saying that if these noblemen of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) were killed, then it's better to die.
I mean, it's so bad what happened, was so bad to him.
He said that, dying is better than living.
And then he started making all of these lines of poetry against Rasool Allah ﷺ, against the Muslims,
all over and he was traveling from one place to another,
for example, after the Battle of Badr(بدر), he goes to Makkah
and spends time with the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), inspiring to fight back.
And it's reported that he didn't leave until, he got the commitment
that they're going to set up an army to go and fight Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Probably they didn't need Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف) to do that.
They will do that on their own initiative,
but this was something that was mentioned in the book.
But what is, a fact is that, he did go to Makkah, after the Battle of Badr(بدر)
to give condolences to the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
I mean, that is something that is reported in various Seerah(سيرة) sources.
And Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف) was getting into no, no areas.
For example, He started describing Muslim women in his poetry
talking about the beauty of so and so, and he would mention names.
And we all know how much respect Muslims have to the honor of their women
and how evil they consider violating the sanctity and the privacy of a Muslim women.
I mean, that's a greatest crime in Islam.
So, Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف) was getting into that area.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said;
مَنْ لِكَعْبِ بْنِ الْأَشْرَفِ فَإِنَّهُ قَدْ آذَى اللَّهَ وَرَسُولَهُ
Who will rid us from Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف),
because he has harmed Allah and His messenger.
It was so bad that Rasool Allah ﷺ wanted this man to be assassinated.
Ibn Is'haaq(إبن اسحاق) said;
He then returned to Madina where he composed verses that were suggestive about the Muslim women
and criticized the Prophet of Allah and his followers.
Musa Bin Uqba(موسى بن عقبه) said;
He harmed the Messenger of Allah by ridiculing him in verses.
So, his war was a war of words,
and Hassan Bin Thabit(حسان بن ثابت), the poet of Rasool Allah ﷺ was fighting back.
Now, you might wonder, what's the big deal about poetry?
Well, poetry was the media of the day.
Poetry for the Arabs was, how the news was conveyed, how history was written,
it was done through poetry.
They wouldn't write books about history.
Their history was narrated through poetry.
And this poetry would be handed down from one generation to another.
It was an oral tradition, the Arabs were not literate.
So, their history, their pride, the criticizing of the tribe was all done through poetry.
And one line of poetry could honor a man or a tribe,
and one line of poetry could dishonor a man or tribe,
for example, there's this tribe called Nomair(نمير), one line of poetry wrecked it and destroyed its reputation for good.
فغض الطرف انك من نمير ، فلا كعباً بلغت ولا كلابا
I mean, this one line of poetry was it, it destroyed, it tarnished, the reputation of this tribe of Nomair(نمير).
Now, the poetry could mention facts or fiction,
but doesn't really make a difference, if the people don't know whether the information mentioned in the poetry was true or not.
And that's the case with media today.
I mean, people go by what the media says, regardless of whether it is true or false, it does leave an effect on the people.
So, this was what, Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف) was doing,
it was a media war against Rasool Allah ﷺ
and Rasool Allah ﷺ said;
مَنْ لِكَعْبِ بْنِ الْأَشْرَفِ فَإِنَّهُ قَدْ آذَى اللَّهَ وَرَسُولَهُ
who will rid us of Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف).
Muhammad Ibn Maslama(محمد إبن مسلمه), one of Al-Ansaar(ألأنصار) volunteers,
he said, I will, O Messenger of Allah.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ assigns to him, this mission.
Muhammad Ibn Maslama(محمد إبن مسلمه), in the narration of Al-Bukhari(البخاري),
and Abu Naila(ابونائله) in the narration of Ibn Is'haaq(إبن إسحاق) anyway,
goes to Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف), visit him, alone.
And he says;
This man's arrival among us was a disaster.
He's talking about Muhammadﷺ, he said this man's arrival among us was a disaster.
The Arabs became hostile to us and united against us.
They have cut off our roots, so that our young are deprived and scared.
We and our families are suffering greatly.
This is how Muhammad Ibn Maslama(محمد إبن مسلمه) was trying to win over the trust of Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف).
He said, Muhammad(محمد) came to us and it was a disaster.
What have we done?
All of the Arabs are now united against us.
We are in a state of fear our children are in state of fear.
Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف) said; I am Al-Ashraf(الاشرف)'s son.
Didn't I tell you that things would turn out this way?
So, Abu Naila(ابونائله) said; What I wanted was for you to sell us some food,
for which we would give you security, a pledge because we're in need.
So, Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف) said; You pledged your women, as a security,
a pledge that you would pay me back.
They said; no way we can't hand over our women to you
and you're such a handsome man and all of that stuff so...
He said, All right, what else, will you pledge, pledge you sons.
He said, No, we cannot pledge and keep our kids with you.
And after that it will be a stigma on them for the rest of their life
that they were left as hostages for some small amount of food.
So, Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف) said; then what do you want to pledge,
what security you'll give me, to ensure that you will pay me back.?
They said we'll bring our weapons.
Weapons are expensive. So, that was a good deal.
And Muhammad Ibn Maslama(محمد إبن مسلمه) and Abu Naila(ابو نائله) said that they're going to pledge their weapons
because they didn't want Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف) to be suspicious, when they bring their weapons.
This was all part of the plot.
So they go back, and they arrange a team of five men.
And they visit Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف) at night, at the appointed time
to deliver their weapons and receive the food.
So, Ka'ab(كعب) heard the calling of Abu Naila(ابو نائله)
and Abu Naila(ابو نائله) was the brother of Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف) from Radha'a(رضاعه) from nursing.
See in Islam, when a woman nurses two children,
they're considered as brothers in Radha'a(رضاعه), brothers because of breastfeeding.
So, this was the relationship of Abu Naila(ابونائله) to Ka'ab(كعب).
So, he calls Ka'ab(كعب) at night.
Apparently, Ka'ab(كعب) just got married.
So he stood up, to respond to the call.
So, his wife told him, where are you going at this time of late hour at night?
He said, This is my brother Abu Naila(ابونائله) calling me.
She said; I can hear blood, dripping from his voice.
He said, This is my brother Abu Naila(ابونائله).
And if a man is called to a stabbing, he should respond.
Meaning even, if there is some evil intention, a man should respond to that.
But Ka'ab(كعب) wasn't suspicious,
Ka'ab(كعب) trusted Abu Naila(ابونائله)
and because of the relationship that they had,
and also, because he thought that they are allied with him against Muhammadﷺ.
So, he goes down, and they talked to him for some time.
And then they said, Ka'ab(كعب), how about we go and take a walk in Shaib Al-Ajooz(شعب العجوز).
He said, All right, fine.
So, they wanted to take him away from his fortress because he was living in a fort.
And he was in a state of war with the Muslims, so he had guards and protection.
They wanted to take him away.
So, they started walking away from his fort, and this is late at night.
Abu Naila(ابونائله) or Muhammad Ibn Maslama(محمد إبن مسلمه), depending on the narration anyway,
puts his hand in the hair of Ka'ab(كعب).
Why did he do that?
He asked Ka'ab(كعب), he said, What is this beautiful smell, that is coming from you?
He said, Well, I was with this woman, who was the most beautiful and all of that,
and I had this cent on.
So, Muhammad(محمد إبن مسلمه) said; Would you allow me to smell it?
He said, Go ahead.
So he grabbed his hair, to smell this perfume.
And he has already agreed with his men, that he would give them a signal to, when to attack.
So, after they walked for a while, he said; can I smell it again Ka'ab(كعب) said; Go ahead.
So this time he grabbed his head and said; attack him.
And they started stabbing him with their swords, but apparently had armor on.
So they were not able to kill him.
And he was screaming very loud and now suddenly all of the lights were going up in the fortresses.
But then Muhammad Ibn Maslama(محمد إبن مسلمه) said;
I had a knife with me and I stabbed him in his lower abdomen
and I cut his abdomen, open, until he fell down.
And when we realize that the man would die, then we left.
However, one of them was stabbed by mistake by one of their swords.
And while they were rushing away, because as we said
he screamed, and now they were all going to respond to the call of Ka'ab(كعب).
So, they had to run.
But this man, who was injured was losing a lot of blood and he was becoming weaker.
So, they had to carry him.
And then Rasool Allah ﷺ met them at the outskirts of Madina.
And he immediately placed his hand on the injury and it was healed.
Now a few comments on this event.
First talk about lessons from Bannu Qainuqah(بنو قينقاع).
And then comment on the assassination of Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف).
Number one, the Messenger of Allah waged war against Bannu Qainuqah(بنو قينقاع) for the sake of one Muslim woman,
to defend her.
This tells you how important it is to protect the rights of Muslim woman.
And now when we hear the calls of the Muslim women from all over the Muslim world,
and nobody responds back that shows that there are no men left.
Because a Muslim man would jump to the defense of his sister.
This is what Rasool Allah ﷺ did!.
And this was the Sunnah(سنة) that was followed by the Khulafa'a(خلفاء), after him,
like Al-Mu'tasim(ألمعتصم) the Khaleefah(خليفه) of Bannu Abbas(بنو عباس),
when one woman said: Wa-Mutasimmaa(وا معتصماہ),
he responded by sending an army to fight with the superpower of his time, the Roman Empire.
And part of the reason, why Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف) was assassinated was
because he was speaking about Muslim women.
Lessons from the assassination of Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف),
The Sahabah took their word seriously.
When Muhammad Ibn Maslama(محمد إبن مسلمه) volunteered to kill Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن اشرف).
For three days after that he lost appetite and was barely eating what was keeping him alive.
That news was delivered to Rasool Allah ﷺ.
So, Rasool Ullah called him and said;
Muhammad Ibn Maslama(محمد إبن مسلمه), what happened.
Muhammad(محمد) said: O Messenger of Allah
I have given my word, and I'm worried that I wouldn't be able to fulfill it.
Muhammad Ibn Maslama(محمد إبن مسلمه), since he pledged to fulfill this mission, he was worried that probably could fail,
he was worried whether he would succeed or not.
He was worried whether his plan is good enough or not.
And he couldn't eat for three days, not because he was afraid of dying.
But because he wanted to make sure that he fulfills his pledge to Rasool Allah ﷺ.
This shows you how seriously the Sahabah took their word.
If they gave their word they had to fulfill it.
Now we throw our words right and left and we don't worry whether we(fulfill it or not).
It's not that we wouldn't worry about them, we even forget about them.
You know, making promises is taken so lightly now.
We throw promises right and left without caring whether we would fulfill them or not.
Muhammad Ibn Maslama(محمد إبن مسلمه) said: I'll do it
And he took that very seriously, and he couldn't eat or drink or sleep.
Rasool Allah ﷺ told him.
اِنَّمَا عَلَيْكَ الْجَحَدْ
You do your best
That is what Allahعَزّوجَلّ will hold you accountable for, whether you did your best or not.
And then if the mission succeeds, or not, as long as you've done your best, Allahعَزّوجَلّ will accept that, from you.
You are not responsible for the outcome of the mission.
You are responsible to do your best.
And this is a lesson for us, we should do our best,
we should try to achieve perfection in anything that we do.
This is very important for Muslims today because as I said, we take our words lightly.
And it's a sign of a Munafiq(منافق) to make a promise that you don't fulfill.
Muhammad Ibn Maslama(محمد إبن مسلمه), after that said, then allow me to speak about you.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said; Go ahead.
Muhammad Ibn Maslama(محمد إبن مسلمه) felt that in order for his mission to succeed,
he would have to speak against Rasool Allah ﷺ.
And that was sanctioned by Rasul Ullah.
So, this tells us thatif Muhammad Ibn Maslama(محمد إبن مسلمه), was allowed to say things that are Kuffr(كفر),
in order for his mission to succeed.
Then a Muslim is allowed to do things that are less than Kuffr(كفر).
For example, if a Muslim spy is among the enemy's army, how would he pray.?
So, such a person as the scholars said,
If he cannot pray standing, then he can pray sitting,
if he cannot pray sitting, then he can pray with his moving his finger.
If he cannot even do that, then he could pray with moving his eyes,
If he's afraid that his mission might be compromised.
So, Muhammad Ibn Maslama(محمد إبن مسلمه) spoke words that are Kuffr(كفر),
he went to Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف) and said; This man was a disaster on us,
but that was allowed.
So, this tells you that there are some special rulings for military operations.
If the mission depends on a person hiding their identity, Islamic identity, then that is allowed.
The next lesson; Ka'ab(كعب) was a Jew,
but ethnically, he was an Arab.
So, that shows that our negative attitude toward the Jews is not based on racism
is not because of their ethnicity.
So, we say the truth, we are not anti Semitic.
Our problem is not with the ethnicity, our problem is with the mindset.
You know, this has to be clear that
Muslims don't have anything against the Jews because of their genetic makeup.
That's not the case or because they belong to a certain culture or certain race, that's not the issue.
And it's unlike, you know, for example, with Hitler with the Nazis,
their problem was racism.
They considered that their race was superior to the race of Al-Yahood(اليهود).
And when some Muslims are accused of being racist or similar to the Nazis, that's furthest from the truth.
The issue with the Muslims is not a problem with the ethnicity of Al-Yahood(اليهود),
it is with the mindset that leads such a people, to become blasphemous against Allahعَزّوجَلّ,
to speak against Rasool Allah ﷺ, to reject his message, to plot against Muslims, to cause disunity,
it is against the evil actions, themselves.
Finally, not all battles are played out on the battlefield.
Sometimes clandestine, special operations are needed to inflict harm on the enemies of Allah
and this was the case with Ka'ab Ibn Al-Ashraf(كعب ابن الاشرف).
صَلَّى الله عَلى سَيَّدِنَا محمد وَعَلى اَلِهِ وَ صَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ تَسْلِيْمًا كَثِيْرًا
وَالسلام عليكم ورحمة الله وبركاته